现在，让我们使用 Visual Studio 代码进入 dev 容器。
Let's get into dev containers
with Visual Studio Code now.
作为微软的一个项目经理，在 Visual Studio Code上工作。
So being a program manager at Microsoft,
works on Visual Studio Code.
我很想告诉你这事但是
I'm obviously a little incentivized
to tell you about this, but
我也很兴奋。
I'm also very excited about it.
我觉得这是关于 Visual Studio 代码的最酷的特点之一
I think this is one of the coolest
features about Visual Studio Code,
这就是为什么不能把它关起来
that's why just cannot shut up about it.
这些叫做 " 开发容器 "
So these are called dev containers that
we're gonna get into with regards to
Visual Studio 代码。
Visual Studio Code.
首先，如果你不是 Visual Studio Code 用户，
So first of all,
if you're not a Visual Studio Code user,
我只邀请你去下载
I'm just gonna invite you to go ahead,
download it and
跟我一起试一下如果你不喜欢的话你可以把它卸了
try it out with me and you can uninstall
it afterwards if you don't like it.
我想说的另一件事是 Burke Holland 有一个免费的课程
And the other thing I wanted to call out
is Burke Holland has a free course on
前端是如何使用 Visual Studio 代码进行级别的主控。
Frontend Masters of how to level
up with Visual Studio Code.
真的很棒完全可以和你的朋友分享
It's really great and totally free so you
can totally share it with your friends and
同事。
coworkers.
好了我们要和远程容器一起工作
Okay, so we're gonna be working with
something called the remote containers
扩展。
extension.
所以有几个远程扩展
So there are several remote
extensions that have come out of
最近是 Visual Studio 代码。
Visual Studio Code recently.
其中一个是 WSL，因此您可以将 Visual Studio 代码连接到 WSL。
One of them is WSLs, so you can have your
Visual Studio Code connected to WSL.
其中一个是 SSH ，所以您可以说任何可以 SSH 的框，
One of them is SSH, so
you can say any box that you can SSH into,
您现在也可以连接到 Visual Studio 代码，这真的很酷，但是
you can now connect to Visual Studio Code
too, which is really cool, but
让我进入远程容器
let me get into the remote
containers one So
我们会为其中一个项目创建第二个 Docker 文件
we're gonna create a second Docker
file for one of these projects,
如果你能挑选其中的任何一个
it doesn't really matter which one so
you can pick any one of these,
节点的其中一个节点。
the one of the node ones.
所以，让我们进入我们的项目文件夹。
So let's go ahead and
go into our projects folder.
我们不能在雨果里这么做我们要去做
We're not gonna do this in Hugo,
we're gonna do it in.
让我们来做这个吧
Let's do, which one is this?
让我们来做一个更复杂节点的应用，好吗 ?
Let's do this one, the
more-complicated-node application, okay?
这个有一个 Docker 文件，做很多好事。
So this one has a Docker file
that does lots of good things.
这就是我们生产的产品，对吧 ?
And this is our production
one that we have, right?
所以我们要在这里创建另一个目录
So we're gonna create another
directory here inside of
一个更复杂节点的应用
a more-complicated-node app one.
再一次你可以在他们的任何一个
And again,
you could do this in anyone of them,
不必是更复杂节点的应用
doesn't have to be
the more-complicated-node app.
这就是我现在要做的
That's just what I'm
gonna do in right now.
我要你在这里创建一个新的文件夹
I want you to create a new folder in here.
这个要叫 . devcontainer，很重要的
This one is gonna be called .devcontainer,
it's very important that this be
尤其如此，因为 Visual Studio Code 正在寻找点或
called particularly that, because
Visual Studio Code is looking for dot or
.devcontainer 中的句点 devcontainer ，
period devcontainer
Inside of .devcontainer,
我希望您输入一个新文件，该文件将成为 Docker 文件。
I want you to put a new file,
which is gonna be a Docker file.
您可以在此处定义开发环境的外观。
This is where you would define what
your development environment looks.
所以我们就在这里说我们要从 12 号节点开始
So let's just say for our sake here, we're
gonna be doing it from node 12-stretch.
我们需要一些东西安装在这里。
And we need a couple
things installed in here.
所以我们要说的是 " RUN npm " 安装 - 全球，
So we're gonna say,
RUN npm install --global,
埃斯特特和漂亮的人
eslint and prettier.
让我们说，这些是我们特定项目需要的两个工具。
Let's say that those are the two tools
that we need for our particular project.
但你可以在这里放任何东西
But you can put anything in here,
你可以把堆跟踪和各种东西放在这里
you can put stack tracing and
all sorts of stuff in here as well.
您需要的任何依赖关系。
Any sort of dependency that you'll need.
这对现在是好的
This is good for now though,
这就是我们要把集装箱装好然后跑的所有东西
this is everything that we're gonna need
to get our container up and running.
请注意我不打算在这里放个 CMD
Notice that I'm not
gonna put a CMD in this,
因为它不是关于运行任何特定命令的，对吧 ?
because it's not actually about
running any particular command, right?
是关于建立一个环境的问题。
It's about setting up an environment.
好的，我们需要为 Docker 文件执行所有操作。
Okay, so that 's all we need to do for
our Docker file.
然后在该 Docker 文件的目录下，在 devcontainer 中
Then next to that Docker file,
same directory, in the devcontainer
我们将创建另一个名为 devcontainer.json的文件。
directory we're gonna create another
file called devcontainer.json.
现在，关键在这里，不是 .devcontainer.json，它叫 devcontainer.json。
Now, key here, not .devcontainer.json,
it's called devcontainer.json.
此处的名称非常重要，因此请将其命名为 devcontainer.json。
The name here is quite important so please
make it called the devcontainer.json.
它必须在 .devcontainer 目录中。
And it must be in
the .devcontainer directory.
这里我们可以给 Visual Studio 代码提供一些信息
And here we can give a bunch of
information to Visual Studio Code so
这特别适用于 Visual Studio Code，
this is specifically for
Visual Studio Code,
为您的项目设置的所有内容。
of all the things that you want set up for
your project.
所以你可以给它一个名字
So you can give it a name, and
这样你就能从不同的窗户里看出来
that's the way you can kinda tell
it apart from different windows.
所以我们要把这个叫做 Froncend Masters 样本
So we're gonna call this one
the Frontend Masters Sample, but
你可以随便给它打个电话
you can call it whatever you want.
我们会关门的
We'll close that.
您要将其指向 Docker 文件所在的位置，因此
You're gonna point it to
where the Docker file is, so
您可以在任何位置放置 Docker 文件。
you can put your Docker
file anywhere you want.
我们正好在这里我要把它叫做 Dockerfile 的库
Ours is just happens to be here, I'm gonna
call it Dockerfile cuz that's where it is.
appPort，这在端口 3000 上运行，因为这是我们做的。
The appPort, This runs on port 3000,
because that's where we made it.
但你可以在这里展示你需要的各种不同港口。
But you could expose all of the various
different ports here that you need to.
所以我可以把 8080 和 blah blah 之类的东西
So I can put 8080 and blah blah blah,
all that kind of stuff,
但现在我们只需要 3000口
but for now we're just gonna do port 3000.
运行程序，所以这是我们运行应用程序的方式。
runArgs, so this is how we're
going to run the application.
我们要做 -u 公共节点来运行节点。
We're gonna do -u common node to run node.
然后我们要做准备
And then here, we're gonna do settings.
在设置中，我们可以为以下项指定不同的设置 :
And inside of settings, we can specify
a bunch of different settings for
Visual Studio 代码本身。
Visual Studio Code itself.
所以，让我们说，非常重要的是，我们希望所有用户都能
So let's say that it was very important
that we wanted all of our users to
使用特定主题。
use a particular theme.
我不知道你为什么要这么做但你可以的对吧
I don't know why you would do that,
but you can, right?
我们要这么做我们会说工作台
So we're gonna do that,
we're gonna say workbench,
这样你就能自动完成这些了吧
that's nice that lets you kind of
autocomplete all these as well, right?
当您在此处执行 workbench.colorTheme 时。
When you do workbench.colorTheme
right there.
这里有我所有的人都知道了它知道他们是什么
And here it has all of mine listed out,
cuz it knows what they are.
我们要从另一个最喜欢的
And we're gonna do a theme
from one of our other favorite
Fronpend Masters 教练， Sarah Drasner ，称夜猫头鹰。
Frontend Masters instructors,
Sarah Drasner, called Night Owl.
好了我们要做终端了
Okay, and then we're gonna do terminal,
.integrated,
.shell， .linux。
.shell, .linux.
我们为什么要这么做
Now why are we gonna do this?
当你进入容器后一旦你进入容器
Because once you get into the container,
once you're inside the container,
针对它编程，您想能够指定哪个 shell 是正确的。
programming against it, you wanna be able
to specify which shell is the correct one.
因此，例如在我的本地计算机上，我有一个设置，所以 Zsh 是我的缺省 shell。
So for example on my local computer I
have a set so Zsh is my default shell.
当我进入这个容器的时候它必须是巴什的
And when I get inside of this
container it needs to be bash.
所以我就会有特别的具体情况
And so
I'm just gonna be specific about it and
表示 bin/bash 是要使用的正确终端。
say that bin/bash is
the correct terminal to use.
我要说 postCreateCommand
I'm gonna say postCreateCommand.
这就是我们进入抚养权的地方，对吧 ?
This is where we get into
the dependency thing, right?
因为一旦我们进入容器内
Because once we're inside the container,
once the container is up and
运行，然后我们想运行 npm 安装，对吗 ?
running, then we wanna run npm install,
right?
这就是我们要做的
So that's what we're gonna do.
在我运行 npm 安装时创建容器之后，安装该类型的容器
After it's finished creating the container
when I run npm install that kind of
绕过不具有正确依赖性和节点模块的问题，
sidesteps the issue of not having
the correct dependencies and node modules,
都是些什么东西
all kind of stuff.
好吧接下来你可以做点很酷的事
Okay, and then here,
something else very cool you can do is you
可以指定要为用户安装哪些扩展，对吗 ?
can specify which extensions that you
want installed for your users, right?
所以有人可以进入你的项目，让我们说你的项目要靠
So someone can come into your project and
let us say your project depends on
每个人都在使用 ESLint and Pretier 和 unit testing ，对吗 ?
everyone using ESLint and
Prettier and unit testing, right?
那你就可以去安装了
So you can go and install for
它们将需要运行项目的所有扩展。
them all the extensions that they
are gonna need to run the project.
首先我们做了夜间猫头鹰的缺省值
So first of all, we made Night Owl
the default that does actually come with
缺省情况下，必须指定 Visual Studio 代码，因此请安装此主题。
Visual Studio Code by default, so we have
to specify, please install this theme.
所以我们要把 sdras 放在 Sarah Drasner 上
So we're gonna put sdras, for
Sarah Drasner, .night-owl.
然后再为我们安装主题。
And then will go and
install the theme for us.
好的我们会去找斯考特
Okay, we'll do dbaeumer.vscode-eslint,
将安装 ELinint 扩展。
that will install the EsLint extension.
我们会去做 esbernp.prettier-vscode
And we'll do it esbernp.prettier-vscode,
and
它将得到作为 JavaScript 的代码格式化程序的 Prettier 扩展。
that will get the Prettier extension
which is a code formatter for JavaScript.
Esrint 是 Lint 术语，在不明显的情况下。
And the EsLint is a Lint term,
in case that was not obvious.
好吧省省吧
All right, so save that.
现在有几件事是你能做的
Now there's a couple of
things that you can do.
让我们这样做吧
Let's actually do it this way.
现在我在我的档案探索者里
Right now I have here in my file explorer.
我把这些不同的项目都打开了，我想打开
I have all these different projects open,
I wanna open it so
这只是一个更复杂的项目
it's just
the more-complicated-node project.
所以我要把这个降到最低
So for a second, I'm gonna minimize this.
我要打开一个更复杂的节点项目
And I'm gonna open a more-complicated-node
project just itself,
对，就在我的 Visual Studio 代码中。
right, just that in my Visual Studio Code.
现在，如果我单击此处的 " 打开 " 。
So now if I click Open here.
注意上面说的第一句话我发现你有一个 dev 容器
Notice the first thing it says, hey,
I noticed you have a dev container
配置文件，要在容器中打开此文件吗 ?
configuration file,
do you wanna open this in the container?
所以我想说我愿意谢谢你
So I'm gonna say, yes, I would, thank you.
在这里你可以看到它正在打开一个遥远的
So down here you can see
that it's opening a remote.
然后单击此处的详细信息，您可以看到它实际上正在运行
And click details here, and
you can see it's actually running
Docker 在我的特定 dev 容器的后台构建。
the Docker build in the background for
my particular dev container.
一旦完成了它就会为我和
And so once it's done that,
then it's gonna run it for me and
它会把我连接到正在运行的容器
it's going to attach me
to the running container.
其实我要在容器里做开发
I'm actually gonna be doing development
inside of the container and
所有东西都在容器里工作
everything would be working
inside of the container.
然后就会用那些暴露了的港口
But then it's going to be
using those port exposing so
我可以在本地主机上运行代码
that I could actually run the code
locally in my local host.
所以这需要一秒的时间
So this will take a second,
there's a bunch of stuff for
你把一切都准备好了
you to get everything working and ready.
所以如果它没有弹出来，在 dev 容器中重新打开，或者如果你想
So if it didn't pop up,
reopen in dev container, or if you wanna
在弹出式弹开后就做，现在不在我的表上。
do it after the pop-up goes away,
right now it doesn't show it on mine.
但在左下角有两个小尖括号，对吧 ?
But in the bottom left there's two little
angle brackets next to each other, right?
如果单击该选项，那么应该有一个在容器中重新打开的选项。
If you click that, there should be
an option to reopen in container.
如果你现在使用的是 Windows ，具体是在 WSL 中，
If you're using Windows right now and
you're in WSL specifically,
你得离开 WSL
you have to get out of WSL.
因此，您必须单击同一徽标，然后在 Windows 中重新打开。
So you have to click that same logo and
say reopen in Windows and
那它就会问你
then it will ask you.
>> 您所做的只是关闭并重新打开。
&gt;&gt; All you did was just close and reopen.
>> Mm - hm，将弹出到您并重新打开此容器。
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm, that'll pop up to you and
reopen this container.
所以我现在是完全不同的主题了，对吧 ?
So notice here now I'm totally
different theme, right?
您可以看到我在 Dev 容器前端主样本。
And you can see here I'm in
Dev Container Frontend Master Sample.
如果我点了点
And here if I click plus,
如果我说猫的问题，你可以看到我在 Debian 里面，对吧 ?
if I say cat /etc/issue you can see
here I'm inside of Debian, right?
所以我现在正在容器里做开发，但是
So I'm actually inside of the container
right now doing development, but
都是同一个项目
it's the same project.
如果我说节点 index.js ，那么它将运行我的项目。
If I say node index.js
it'll run my project.
如果我打开它你会看到它还在运转
And if I open this,
You'll see that it's still running.
你甚至可以看到它在另一个端口上打开了它。
You can even see that it
opened it on a different port.
我甚至都不知道它会这样做但它只是为了你
I didn't even know it was gonna do that,
but it just kinda does that for you.
这里是 VS .
It's coming back here to VS Code.
我现在在这里有个小探险家
I now have this little
remote explorer over here.
您可以在此处看到 " 远程资源管理器 " 。
You can see here, Remote Explorer.
它应该告诉我这里会有
It should tell me,
there it's gonna be in here.
在这里转发的港口
So here the forwarded ports,
我可以看到它的所有端口，以及它们的位置和位置。
I can actually see all the ports that it's
forwarding and where they're going to and
我可以重新配置它们还有一堆类似的东西
I can reconfigure them and
a bunch of stuff like that as well.
有问题吗
Any questions?
> > 这就是我想思考的。
&gt;&gt; Here's what I'm trying to think.
所以一切都很棒你在容器里做开发
So it's all great, you're in the
container, you're doing the development
我假设你的所有内容都被保存了对吧
there, I'm assuming that's where
all your contents are saved, right?
现在，您要落实并基本遵循常规工作流程。
Now you wanna commit and
basically follow your regular workflow.
那是怎么工作的
How does that work?
只是例行的吗
Just the regular way?
> > 所以它是有约束力的，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; So it's a bind bound, right?
所以它实际上是写在主机操作系统上。
So it's actually writing to
the host operating system.
> > 这就是它的意思吗 ?
&gt;&gt; So that's what it does?
> > 恩，好的问题。
&gt;&gt; Yep, good question.
你让它工作了吗
Did you get it to work?
> > 我还在研究呢
&gt;&gt; I'm still working on it.
>> 还在处理吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Still work on it?
> > 是。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
> > 是啊， Windows 和 WSL 有点，
&gt;&gt; Yeah, with Windows and
WSL it's a little,
我们要在这方面做得更好
working on that we're gonna make
that a better experience but for
现在你必须退出 WSL 然后重新连接
right now you have to exit out of WSL and
then reconnect it.
在这里的任何时候，我都可以说，点击这里的这个小东西。
Here at any time though I can say,
clicking on this little thing down here.
我可以说 " 关闭远程连接 " 或您想要的任何内容。
I can say Close Remote Connection or
whatever you want.
实际上，就说，关闭远程连接。
And actually, just says,
Close Remote Connection.
这会把我送回正常的 VS .
This will send me back
into normal VS Code land.
然后你就可以在容器里重新打开文件夹对吧
And then down here you can always say
reopen folder in container, right?
所以你随时都能做到这些
So you can do all that
stuff up at anytime.
让我们看看吧
So let's see.
所以我想向你们展示如何对你的同事有点邪恶，对它很有趣。
So I wanna show you how to be a little
bit evil to your coworkers, cuz it's fun.
这是哪儿
Where is this?
所以我们要再次打开它
So we're just gonna open this again, and
我们要打开一个更复杂的项目
we're gonna open
the more-complicated-node project.
所以现在我不能打开同一个容器
So right now I'm not gonna
open the same container,
我们要在这里再做一次
we're gonna do it here in just a second.
所以这里有个有趣的愚弄愚弄你的同事
So here is a funny April fools joke
to play on your coworkers, and
别这样对我我会很生气的
do not do it to me,
cuz I will be very upset.
所以我们要回到我们的 devcontainer.json
So we 're gonna go back over
here to our devcontainer.json.
而不是在夜猫头鹰的情况下我们要做热狗的准备
And instead of being on Night Owl,
we're gonna make this Hot Dog Stand.
所以我们要做热狗的准备
So we're gonna make this Hot Dog Stand.
而不是在这里装夜猫头鹰
And instead of installing
Night Owl right here,
我们要把它放在热狗摊上
we're going to put
somekittens.hot-dog-stand.
现在我要警告这会烧掉你的眼珠
Now I'm going to warn this is going
to burn your eyeballs as soon as
我们重新打开这个
we reopen this.
所以如果你不想让你的眼珠烧掉
So if you don't want your eyeballs burnt,
现在就别再打开一个容器了
just don't click open
a container right now.
好了现在我们有了这个我要点击这个
Okay, so now that we have that,
I'm gonna click this and
说在集装箱里重新开放对吧
say, Reopen in Container, right?
所以它将会经历并重建这个容器。
So it's gonna go through and
rebuild the container.
我要点击重建
I'm gonna click Rebuild.
所以我那天发现的热狗主题其实是从 Windows 3.1开始的。
So a Hot Dog theme I found out the other
day is actually from Windows 3.1.
有个主题可以放在 Windows 3.1 上
There was a theme that you can
put on Windows 3.1 that was just
全世界最糟糕的主题
the worst theme in the entire world.
有人为 Visual Studio 代码重新创建了它。
And someone recreated it for
Visual Studio Code.
这很恐怖。
And it is just horrifying.
我连看都看不清楚，这让我头疼。
[LAUGH] I can not even look at it for
very long, it gives me a headache.
所以如果你有一个工作的容器
So if you have a dev container for
your work,
只要把这个改为热狗容器你就会得到这个怪物
just go change this to Hot Dog container
and you get this just monstrosity.
好吧我得停了
Okay, I have to stop.
我对现在在那里受伤的所有人都很抱歉
I'm so sorry to all the people
I've harmed out there now.
但很酷，你可以做各种疯狂的事情。
But pretty cool, and
you can do all sorts of crazy stuff.
在缺省情况下，您可以继续使用 " Times New Roman " 或 " Times New Roman " 。
You can go on and make the font Times
New Roman by default or something that.
或者 Comic Sans，我们应该做漫画漫画。
Or Comic Sans,
we should have done Comic Sans.
总之下次吧
Anyway, next time.
好的，我们会关闭远程连接。
[LAUGH] All right, so
we'll close remote connection.
这就是我想给你看的  。
That's all I wanted to show
you with Visual Studio Code.
我认为这对于你和你的团队来说是一个真正具有吸引力的工作流程，对吧 ?
I think this is a truly compelling
workflow for you and your team, right?
你可以和你的发展容器一起
You could all just come up
with your dev container and
只要有人打开他们的 Visual Studio 代码
then as soon as someone just opens
their Visual Studio Code with that, and
我们会在一个容器里给你打开这个
there's, ey, we're gonna open
this in a container for you.
它会为你设定一切，坐等，
It will set everything up for
you, just sit back and wait, and
一旦完成了一切都将为你工作
then once it's done,
everything will just be working for you.
我没有给你看但发生的事是埃斯林特
The thing I didn't show you but
was happening is EsLint and
也会自动安装 Pretier 。
Prettier were automatically
installed as well.
所以如果我开始保存我的作品就会自动格式化
So if I started saving my work,
it would automatically be formatting and
把我的代码给我从盒子里出来也很棒
wanting my code for me just out
of the box, which is great too.